Electrical Engineer

Skilled and self-driven bilingual professional with progressive experience working in electronics and electrical engineering. A team player with a demonstrated ability in determining effective methods to ensure efficiency while meeting demanding deadlines. Very hands on, highly organized and a faster learner with strong communication skills and a focus on expanding career experience in a high level professional environment. Areas of Expertise:

- Hardware Testing and Validation
- CAD Software
- COTS Electrical Test Equipment
- Technical Documentation

- Project Management
- Systems Design and Development
- Emotional Intelligence
- Collaborative Leadership

Experience

Alpine Electronics Research of America – Torrance, CA

Product Evaluation Engineer Associate II, July 2014 - March 2016

Product Evaluation Engineer I, April 2016 – March 2019

Job description

July 2014 - 2019

- Set up and operate various test equipment to build efficient testing environment.
- Determine effective methods to obtain valid test results to meet assigned deadlines.
- Interpret and record test results in order to identify failure modes and defects.
- Interpret schematic diagrams, pin connector diagrams, and datasheets.
- Responsible for end-user style testing, black box testing, reproducibility testing, regression testing, and exploratory testing on Honda/Acura, BMW, and Alpine brand projects.
- Evaluate Engineering Verification(EVT) and Design Verification(DVT) samples to ensure Alpine aftermarket infotainment systems meet quality standards before mass production.
- Evaluate Bluetooth compatibility and functionality between infotainment hardware and Bluetooth enabled smart devices.
- Provide peer review and seek peer review on project reports to ensure quality deliverables
- Adhere to ISO 9001 standards
- Maintain up to date record of work done and complete a balanced score card at the end of the fiscal year.
- Assemble wire harnesses and install critical components on test benches and vehicles.
- Develop Excel check sheets and test cases from stakeholder specifications, interpret test results, and prepare project reports using MS PowerPoint.
- Assist the development of test plans, schedules, and recommend resource procurement for Alpine aftermarket infotainment systems.
- Participate as software tester and evaluator in agile development process in collaboration with Alpine software development team.
- Report and document software issues on Redmine or GitLab repository to help developers comprehend and reproduce software issues.

Education

Bachelor of Science (BS), Electronics and Computer Engineering (2013)

California State Polytechnic University, Pomona

Relevant Courses

- DC/AC circuit analysis
- Semiconductor devices and circuits
- Electronic manufacturing and PCB fabrication
- Industrial electronics
- FPGA Systems
- Microcontroller systems

- Feedback systems technology
- Data communication and networking

Certifications/Trainings

Six Sigma Green Belt (2019) Solid Works Essentials (2020)

Technical Skills

- Multi-meters, oscilloscopes, and power supplies
- Spectrum analyzers
- Generators
- Circuit design PSpice
- PCB design and fabrication
- Transistors, Capacitors, Super Capacitors, Inductors
- Soldering tools
- Power tools

• Introduction to Solid Works

- Adobe Photoshop
- Adobe Audition
- Redmine
- Office 360
- Audacity Software
- Solid Works
- Gitlab
- PSpice Simulation program
- Google SketchUp